Pujari: First Lord Ganesha, then Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati, Mahakali.
Pujari: Prima il Signore Ganesha, poi Mahalakshmi, Mahasaraswati, Mahakali.
Then Lord Kalki and then Lord Kalki and Sahastrara Swamini.
Poi il Signore Kalki ed infine il Signore Kalki e Sahastrara Swamini.
Yogi: Three times Shri Ganesha? Pujari: Hm?
Yogi: Tre volte Shri Ganesha? Pujari: Come?
Yogi: How many times the Ganesha mantra? Pujari: Each once, I mean.
Yogi: Quante volte il mantra a Ganesha? Pujari: Intendo ognuno per una volta.
Gli yogi: Om Twameva Sakshat, Shri Ganesha Sakshat,
Gli yogi: Om Twameva Sakshat, Shri Ganesha Sakshat,
Shri Adi Shakti Sakshat,
Shri Adi Shakti Sakshat,
Shri Bhagavati Sakshat, Shri Mataji,
Shri Bhagavati Sakshat, Shri Mataji,
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Om Twameva Sakshat Shri Mahalakshmi,
Om Twameva Sakshat Shri Mahalakshmi,
Mahasaraswati, Mahakali Trigunatmika,
Mahasaraswati, Mahakali Trigunatmika,
Kundalini Sakshat, Shri Adi Shakti Sakshat,
Kundalini Sakshat, Shri Adi Shakti Sakshat,
Shri Bhagavati Sakshat, Shri Mataji,
Shri Bhagavati Sakshat, Shri Mataji,
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Om Twameva Sakshat Shri Kalki Sakshat,
Om Twameva Sakshat Shri Kalki Sakshat,
Shri Adi Shakti Sakshat,
Shri Adi Shakti Sakshat,
Shri Bhagavati Sakshat, Shri Mataji,
Shri Bhagavati Sakshat, Shri Mataji,
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Om Twameva Sakshat Shri Kalki Sakshat,
Om Twameva Sakshat Shri Kalki Sakshat,
Shri Sahastrara Swamini Moksha Pradayini Mataji,
Shri Sahastrara Swamini Moksha Pradayini Mataji,
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Pujari: Now the names of Lord Vishnu. Om Shri Keshavaya Namah,
Pujari: Ora i nomi del Signore Vishnu. Om Shri Keshavaya Namah,
Om Shri Narayanaya Namah, Om Shri Madhavaya Namah,
Om Shri Narayanaya Namah, Om Shri Madhavaya Namah,
Om Shri Govindaya Namah, Om Shri Vishnuve Namah,
Om Shri Govindaya Namah, Om Shri Vishnuve Namah,
Om (Shri) Madhusudanaya Namah, Om Shri Trivikramaya Namah,
Om (Shri) Madhusudanaya Namah, Om Shri Trivikramaya Namah,
Om Shri Vamanaya Namah, Om Shri Shridharaya Namah,
Om Shri Vamanaya Namah, Om Shri Shridharaya Namah,
Om Shri Hrishikeshaya Namah, Om Shri Sankarshanaya Namah,
Om Shri Hrishikeshaya Namah, Om Shri Sankarshanaya Namah,
Om Shri Vasudevaya Namah, Om Shri Pradyumnaya Namah,
Om Shri Vasudevaya Namah, Om Shri Pradyumnaya Namah,
Om Shri Aniruddhaya Namah, Om Shri Purushottamaya Namah,
Om Shri Aniruddhaya Namah, Om Shri Purushottamaya Namah,
Om Shri Aghokshajaya Namah, Om Shri Narasimhaya Namah,
Om Shri Aghokshajaya Namah, Om Shri Narasimhaya Namah,
Om Shri Achyutaya Namah, Om Shri Janardanaya Namah,
Om Shri Achyutaya Namah, Om Shri Janardanaya Namah,
Om Shri Padmanabhaya Namah, Om Shri Damodaraya Namah,
Om Shri Padmanabhaya Namah, Om Shri Damodaraya Namah,
Om Shri Upendraya Namah, Om Shri Haraye Namah,
Om Shri Upendraya Namah, Om Shri Haraye Namah,
Om Shri Krishnaye Namah.
Om Shri Krishnaye Namah.
Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Mataji: Why these twenty-one names are taken before every puja,
Shri Mataji: Perché questi ventuno nomi sono recitati prima di ogni puja,
even before the today renovation of it?
anche prima del puja così come è stato rinnovato oggi?
First you have to worship Shri Ganesha.
Per prima cosa dovete rendere omaggio a Shri Ganesha.
But even before worshipping why these names are taken,
Ma è importante capire per quale motivo questi nomi siano recitati
is important to understand, everything has a why.
addirittura prima dell’adorazione. Ogni cosa ha un motivo.
Because these are the twenty-one channels within your Sushumna,
Essi rappresentano infatti i ventuno canali all’interno della Sushumna,
twenty-one channels, we should say, in this
anzi, dovremmo dire i ventuno canali compresi
complete Ida, Pingala and Sushumna Nadi.
in tutti e tre i canali principali, cioè Ida, Pingala e Sushumna:
absolutely to give you the ascent, twenty- one channels in Ida, Pingala, Sushumna.
i ventuno canali compresi in tutti e tre i canali, cioè Ida, Pingala e Sushumna.
So one would say seven channels in the Sushumna Nadi.
Si dovrebbe quindi dire che ci sono sette canali nella Sushumna,
But these seven channels are divided multiplied by seven into three.
ma questi sette vanno moltiplicati per tre.
So every channel has got twenty-one (inner? Unclear) channels.
Pertanto, ogni canale consta di ventun canali (interni? Non chiaro).
So Sushumna Nadi has got also twenty-one channels.
Dunque, anche Sushumna nadi ha ventuno canali.
Left-hand side Nadis are as you know that –
Le nadi del lato sinistro sono, come sapete -
perhaps you know, I don’t know if you know the names or not.
forse lo sapete, non so se conosciate i nomi o no.
And the right hand side also, like Gayatri,
Ed anche il lato destro; ad esempio, Gayatri,
Parvati and all these are on the righ hand side.
Parvati e tutti questi nomi sono per il lato destro.
And the left ones are called as Chamundi,
E quelle di lato sinistro sono chiamate Chamundi,
and all these left-sided things, there are seven of them.
e di tutte queste (nadi) del lato sinistro ce ne sono sette.
Now, the central path has got twenty-one channels and has got twenty-one powers.
Ora, il sentiero centrale ha ventuno canali e ventuno poteri.
And their deities are named
E le loro deità hanno nomi
according to the twenty-one aspects of Shri Vishnu.
che si accordano con i ventuno aspetti di Shri Vishnu.
And that’s why these twenty-one aspects are first said,
Ecco perché questi ventuno aspetti sono invocati per primi,
so that within you all these twenty-one channels are awakened.
affinché tutti questi ventuno canali siano risvegliati in voi.
Within you, first of all.
Innanzitutto dentro di voi.
Puja is a double thing, that a cup has to be made
Il puja ha un doppio aspetto: una coppa deve essere creata
and then this source has to be opened out.
e poi deve essere aperta questa sorgente.
So you are the cup. The Sushumna is the channel you have by which you suck in.
Voi siete la coppa, la Sushumna è il canale che avete mediante il quale voi assorbite.
So to open the Sushumna these twenty-one names are said.
Questi ventuno nomi vengono dunque recitati per aprire la Sushumna.
Now, why first Shri Ganesha?
Ora, perché prima Shri Ganesha?
Because Shri Ganesha is the beginning of the desire. And the end of the desire.
Perché Shri Ganesha è l’inizio del desiderio ed è la fine del desiderio.
You start with Ganesha and end up with Ganesha.
Voi iniziate con Ganesha e finite con Ganesha.
And that’s why Shri Ganesha is worshipped.
Ed ecco perché si rende omaggio a Shri Ganesha.
Is the other way round now, the source.
Ora, l’altro aspetto è la sorgente.
When you direct your attention to the source you worship it,
Quando dirigete l’attenzione alla sorgente, la adorate
and when you want to incite or open out your own being, then you chant it.
e, quando volete stimolare o aprire il vostro essere, intonate un mantra.
This is the difference between worship and a mantra.
Questa è la differenza tra l’adorazione e il recitare un mantra.
If you just say mantra, you open yourself up.
Se semplicemente dite un mantra, vi aprite.
But when you worship and chant, then you tap the source.
Ma quando venerate e contemporaneamente intonate un mantra,
I don’t know if I’ve said this before or not.
Non so se l’ho già detto oppure no. Yogi: No, no, no. Shri Mataji: No? Va bene.
That’s how you understand the puja part.
E così che capite la parte relativa al puja.
Now, those who are newcomers, their cup is completely useless.
Ora, la coppa delle persone nuove è del tutto inutile.
And when you excite the deities, they get busy opening their cups,
E quando voi sollecitate le deità, esse si impegnano ad aprire le loro coppe
everybody’s cups also. So it’s a double work.
ed anche le coppe di tutti. È dunque un lavoro doppio.
But if your cup is ready, it’s very easy to fill in.
Ma se la vostra coppa è pronta, è molto facile colmarla.
So now these twenty-one names I think you should take again
Penso dunque che adesso dovreste recitare di nuovo questi ventuno nomi
with the understanding, is better. All right.
con cognizione di causa, è meglio. Bene.
Pujari: Om Shri Keshavaya Namah, Om Shri Narayanaya Namah,
Pujari: Om Shri Keshavaya Namah, Om Shri Narayanaya Namah,
Om Shri Madhavaya Namah, Om Shri Govindaya Namah,
Om Shri Madhavaya Namah, Om Shri Govindaya Namah,
Om Shri Vishnuve Namah, Om (Shri) Madhusudanaya Namah,
Om Shri Vishnuve Namah, Om (Shri) Madhusudanaya Namah,
Om Shri Trivikramaya Namah, Om Shri Vamanaya Namah,
Om Shri Trivikramaya Namah, Om Shri Vamanaya Namah,
Om Shri Shridharaya Namah, Om Shri Hrishikeshaya Namah,
Om Shri Shridharaya Namah, Om Shri Hrishikeshaya Namah,
Om Shri Sankarshanaya Namah, Om Shri Vasudevaya Namah,
Om Shri Sankarshanaya Namah, Om Shri Vasudevaya Namah,
Om Shri Pradyumnaya Namah, Om Shri Aniruddhaya Namah,
Om Shri Pradyumnaya Namah, Om Shri Aniruddhaya Namah,
Om Shri Purushottamaya Namah, Om Shri Aghokshajaya Namah,
Om Shri Purushottamaya Namah, Om Shri Aghokshajaya Namah,
Om Shri Narasimhaya Namah, Om Shri Achyutaya Namah,
Om Shri Narasimhaya Namah, Om Shri Achyutaya Namah,
Om Shri Janardanaya Namah, Om Shri Padmanabhaya Namah,
Om Shri Janardanaya Namah, Om Shri Padmanabhaya Namah,
Om Shri Damodaraya Namah, Om Shri Upendraya Namah,
Om Shri Damodaraya Namah, Om Shri Upendraya Namah,
Om Shri Haraye Namah, Om Shri Krishnaye Namah.
Om Shri Haraye Namah, Om Shri Krishnaye Namah.
Pujari e gli yogi: Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Pujari e gli yogi: Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Mataji: Now.
Shri Mataji: Ora.
Pujari: Now we have the mantra for pranayama.
Pujari: Adesso c’è il mantra per Pranayama. Shri Mataji: Questo è il Gayatri,
Pujari: Pranayama. Shri Mataji: Pranayama is the same thing. Is for –
Pujari: Pranayama. Shri Mataji: Pranayama è la stessa cosa. È per…
Prana is right side. It’s physical side. You are opening the right side.
Prana è il lato destro, il lato fisico. Voi state aprendo il lato destro.
You see, this Gayatri mantra you say. Bhur Bhuva Swaha and all these things.
Voi recitate questo mantra Gayatri: Bhur Bhuva Swaha e tutto il resto.
Now, Bhu is Pruthvi, Bhuva is Antariksha,
Ebbene, Bhu è Pruthvi, Bhuva è Antariksha,
you see, like that, it’s all the centers [Pujari: “Swaha”],
sapete, così, rappresenta tutti i centri [Pujari: “Swaha”],
the essence of the centers, you see? Now, Antariksha –
l’essenza dei centri, capite? Ora, Antariksha –
you’ll be surprised that you are the essence of all the Antariksha,
sarete sorpresi di essere l’essenza di tutto l’Antariksha,
your centers are. Yes.
i vostri centri lo sono. Sì.
Pujari [recites Pranayama prayer]: “Pranavasya Parabrahma rishi
Pujari [recita la preghiera a Pranayama]: “Pranavasya Parabrahma rishi
Paramatma Devata, Devi Gayatri chandah. Pranayame viniyogah.”
Paramatma Devata, Devi Gayatri chandah. Pranayame viniyogah.”
Shri Mataji: You do it only with the one nose? Yogi: Both noses. (Not audible)
Shri Mataji: Lo fai solo con una narice? Yogi: Con entrambe le narici. (Non chiaro)
Shri Mataji: Both the noses. Prana: Prana is right side.
Shri Mataji: Entrambe le narici. Prana: prana è il lato destro.
Prana shakti is right side, Mana shakti is left side.
L’energia di prana è il lato destro. L’energia di mana è il lato sinistro.
So Prana shakti you are exciting
In questo modo stimolate l’energia prana
because this prana is the one which spreads in the body,
perché il prana è quello che si diffonde nel corpo,
gives you the balance, which takes in and gives out.
che vi dà equilibrio, che riceve all’interno e che butta fuori.
Pujari: Now we have the Gayatri mantra.
Pujari: Adesso abbiamo il mantra Gayatri.
Aum bhū, Om bhuvah,
Om bhū, Om bhuvah,
Aum swah, Aum mah,
Om swah, Om mah,
Aum janah, Aum tapah, Aum satyam,
Om janah, Om tapah, Om satyam,
Aum tat-Savitru-varenyam, bhargo devasya dhī-mahi
Om tat-Savitru-varenyam, bhargo devasya dhī-mahi
Dhiyo-yo’nah prachodayāt Aum āpo jyotiras’omṛutam
Dhiyo-yo’nah prachodayāt Om āpo jyotiras’omṛutam
Brahma bhūr-bhuvah swar’om
Brahma bhūr-bhuvah swar’om
Pujari e yogi: Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Pujari e yogi: Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Pujari: Om Sriman Maha-Ganadhipataye namah,
Pujari: Om Sriman Maha-Ganadhipataye namah,
Ishta devata-bhyo namah, kula-devata-bhyo namah,
Ishta devata-bhyo namah, kula-devata-bhyo namah,
grama-devata-bhyo namah. Shri Mataji: These are all pertaining to you.
grama-devata-bhyo namah. Shri Mataji: Tutti questi riguardano voi.
Kula Devata is your dynasty, from where you come. There is a god who looks after that.
Kula Devata è la stirpe dalla quale provenite. C’è una deità che la protegge.
Then Grama Devata, of this village. There is a god who looks after this.
Poi Grama Devata, per questo villaggio. C’è una deità che lo protegge.
Is all for you, pertaining to you. Then -
(Questi mantra) sono tutti per voi, riguardano voi. Poi?
Kula Devata? Pujari: Ishta Devata. Shri Mataji: Ishta, the One -
(Dopo) Kula Devata? Pujari: Ishta Devata. Shri Mataji: Ishta, Colui -
your Ishta Devata is Me.
il vostro Ishta Devata sono io.
Ishta means to whom we worship.
Ishta significa l’oggetto della nostra adorazione.
Pujari: Then: Sthana-devata-bhyo namah.
Pujari: Poi: Sthana-devata-bhyo namah.
Shri Mataji: The god, the god that resides in this area.
Shri Mataji: Il dio, il dio che risiede in quest’area.
Means the Divine part that it resides
Indica l’aspetto divino che risiede
Pujari: Vastu-devata-bhyo namah.
Pujari: Vastu-devata-bhyo namah.
Shri Mataji: The one – I don’t know if they do vastu here, but in every house in India
Shri Mataji: Colui - non so se qui facciano vastu ma in ogni casa indiana
they put a kind of a vastu, means they put certain things
mettono una specie di vastu, ossia mettono alcune cose
inside the foundation to protect the house.
dentro le fondamenta per proteggere la casa.
Pujari: Mata pitrubhyam namah.
Pujari: Mata pitrubhyam namah.
Shri Mataji: And your mother and father they are to be worshipped –
Shri Mataji: Inoltre, vostra madre e vostro padre devono essere onorati –
they are to be saluted because you are part of them.
devono essere omaggiati poiché siete parte di loro.
Pujari: Shri Lakshmi-Narayanabhyam namah.
Pujari: Shri Lakshmi-Narayanabhyam namah.
Sarvebhyo devebhyo namoh namah. Sarvebhyo…
Sarvebhyo devebhyo namoh namah. Sarvebhyo…
Shri Mataji: Lakshmi Narayan is, why… again see, Lakshmi Narayan.
Shri Mataji: Lakshmi Narayan perché… guardate, di nuovo Lakshmi Narayan.
More insistence on Lakshmi Narayan, again, because of the Sushumna, again.
Di nuovo si insiste ancora su Lakshmi Narayan, ancora a causa della Sushumna.
The Void. Lakshmi Narayana. Sarva devobhyo Gurubhyo…
Il Void. Lakshmi Narayana. Sarva devobhyo Gurubhyo…
Pujari: Ah. Sarva gurubhyo Namah.
Pujari: Ah. Sarva gurubhyo Namah.
Shri Mataji: All for your ascent, you see?
Shri Mataji: Tutto per la vostra ascesa, vedete?
Pujari: Sarvebhyo-brahmanebhyo namah. Shri Mataji: All those who are
Pujari: Sarvebhyo-brahmanebhyo namah. Shri Mataji: Tutti coloro che sono
realized souls to be really saluted.
anime realizzate devono essere realmente omaggiati.
All has to do with the ascent, see? How clear-cut it is.
È tutto in relazione con l’ascesa, vedete? Com’è chiaro!
Pujari: Now the twelve names of Lord Ganesha.
Pujari: Ora i dodici nomi del Signore Ganesha.
Shri Mataji: Now. The twelve names of Ganesha because Ganesha must be
Shri Mataji: Ora. I dodici nomi di Ganesha in quanto Ganesha deve essere
awakened within you to begin with first, you see,
risvegliato dentro di voi all’inizio, per prima cosa, sapete.
He must be first of all, and then open the source of Ganesha. Let’s have it.
Prima di tutto Lui deve (essere risvegliato) e poi aprite la sorgente di Ganesha.
Kapilo Gajakarnakah, Lambodarascha, Vikato, Vignanasho Ganadhipah
Kapilo Gajakarnakah, Lambodarascha, Vikato, Vignanasho Ganadhipah
Dhumra-ketur-Ganadhyaksho, Bala-chandro Gajananah
Dhumra-ketur-Ganadhyaksho, Bala-chandro Gajananah
Dvadash-aitani Namani, yah patet shrunu-yad-api
Dvadash-aitani Namani, yah patet shrunu-yad-api
vidya-rambhe vivahe-cha, praveshe nirgame tata
vidya-rambhe vivahe-cha, praveshe nirgame tata
sangrame sankate-chaiva, vignas tasya na jayate.
sangrame sankate-chaiva, vignas tasya na jayate.
Then all the mantras of the various Devas and Devis.
Poi tutti i mantra dei vari dei e dee.
Shukl-ambara-dharam devam, shashi-varnam chatur-bhujam
Shukl-ambara-dharam devam, shashi-varnam chatur-bhujam
prasanna-vadanam dhyayet, sarva vignopa-shantaye.
prasanna-vadanam dhyayet, sarva vignopa-shantaye.
Sarva-mangala mangalye, Shive sarva-arta sadhike
Sarva-mangala mangalye, Shive sarva-arta sadhike
sharanye tryambake Gauri, Narayani namostute.
sharanye tryambake Gauri, Narayani namostute.
Sarvada sarva karyeshu, nasti tesham amangalam
Sarvada sarva karyeshu, nasti tesham amangalam
yesham hridisto bhagavan, mangalayatanam harih.
yesham hridisto bhagavan, mangalayatanam harih.
Tadeva lagnam sudinam tadeva, tara-balam chandra-balam tadeva
Tadeva lagnam sudinam tadeva, tara-balam chandra-balam tadeva
vidya balam daiva-balam tadeva, lakshmi-pateh tenghri yugam smarami.
vidya balam daiva-balam tadeva, lakshmi-pateh tenghri yugam smarami.
Labhas-tesham jayastesham kutastesham parajayah… Shri Mataji: Tesham.
Labhas-tesham jayastesham kutastesham parajayah… Shri Mataji: Tesham.
Labhas-tesham, to Them. Labhas-tesham.
Labhas-tesham, a loro. Labhas-tesham.
Pujari: Yesham indivara shyame hridayaste janardanah.
Pujari: Yesham indivara shyame hridayaste janardanah.
Shri Mataji: All - all about Shri Krishna. All about Shri Vishnu.
Shri Mataji: Tutto, tutto ciò che riguarda Shri Krishna.
Pujari: Vinayakam, Gurum bhanum, Brahma-Vishnu-Maheshwaram
Pujari: Vinayakam, Gurum bhanum, Brahma-Vishnu-Maheshwaram
Saraswatim pranamyadau sarva karyarta siddhaye.
Saraswatim pranamyadau sarva karyarta siddhaye.
Abhipa-sitartha siddhyartham pujito yah surah suraih
Abhipa-sitartha siddhyartham pujito yah surah suraih
sarva-vighna haras tasmai Ganadhi pataye namah.
sarva-vighna haras tasmai Ganadhi pataye namah.
Shri Mataji: Oh, Shri Ganesha’s. Pujari: Yes.
Shri Mataji: Oh, quelli di Shri Ganesha. Pujari: Sì.
(More mantras)
(Altri mantra)
Now we say where this puja is being - all, the time and… Shri Mataji: Yes.
Adesso diciamo dove viene (celebrato) il puja: tutto, l’ora e… Shri Mataji: Sì.
Pujari: Srimad bhagavato mahapurushasya vishnurajnaya pravartamanasya,
Pujari: Srimad bhagavato mahapurushasya vishnurajnaya pravartamanasya,
adya brahmano-dvitiya parardhe vishnupade, sri svetavaraha kalpe,
adya brahmano-dvitiya parardhe vishnupade, sri svetavaraha kalpe,
vaivasvata manvantare - Krita Yuge -
vaivasvata manvantare - Krita Yuge -
England varshe - Europe kande - Cheltenham deshe.
England varshe - Europe kande - Cheltenham deshe.
Shri Mataji: Ne - now why was what… Pujari: Why was what - Manvantare, Mother.
Shri Mataji: Perché era quello…? Pujari: Perché era… Manvantare, Madre.
Shri Mataji: Accha (hindi: yes). Pujari: Krita Yuge.
Shri Mataji: Accha (hindi: sì). Pujari: Krita Yuge.
Shri Mataji: Hm, Kruta Yuge… (hindi).
Shri Mataji: Hm, Kruta Yuge… (hindi).
It’s Kruta Yuge, this is time when you have to do something.
È Kruta Yuge, è il momento in cui dovete fare qualcosa,
Something will actualize, something will work out. This is Kruta Yuga.
in cui si realizzerà qualcosa, qualcosa funzionerà. Questo è Kruta Yuga.
Pujari: Thames uttara tire,
Pujari: Thames uttara tire,
varshaa grishme, shraavana mase,
varshaa grishme, shraavana mase,
shukla pakshe, navami thatau…
shukla pakshe, navami thatau…
(Mantras continue)
(I mantra continuano)
[In the meantime Shri Mataji says: “Yes” to a child while
[Shri Mataji dice: “Sì” ad una bambina
teaching her to keep her hands open.]
mentre le insegna a tenere le mani aperte, ndt]
Mataji Nirmala Devi priityartam - Sarva devi deva…
Mataji Nirmala Devi priityartam - Sarva devi deva…
Pujari e gli yogi: … Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Pujari e gli yogi: … Sakshat Shri Adi Shakti Bhagavati Mataji
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Shri Nirmala Devyai Namoh Namah.
Pujari: (continues with mantras).
(Il pujari continua con i mantra)
Shri Mataji: Shoda Shopachaar. Shoda see, is sixteen.
Shri Mataji: Shoda Shopachaar. Shoda, vedete, significa sedici.
Pujari: Yes. Shoda Shopachaar. Shri Mataji: Hm. Yes. See,
Pujari: Sì. Shoda Shopachaar. Shri Mataji: Hm. Vedete,
whatever I have got, my knowledge, whatever we have got,
qualsiasi cosa io abbia, la mia conoscenza, tutto ciò che abbiamo,
our knowledge, you see, and whatever things we have got,
la nostra conoscenza e qualsiasi cosa abbiamo,
whatever we have got, means whatever we’ve got with us,
tutto ciò che abbiamo, insomma, qualsiasi cosa abbiamo con noi,
we worship You, oh Mother.
noi Ti veneriamo, O Madre.
With our sixteen ways of worship we do to You.
Lo facciamo con i nostri sedici mezzi di adorazione.
[Pujari continues with mantras]
(Il pujari continua con i mantra)